中亦都夠法定人數，噉我哋開會啦，請政府入嚟啦，好嘛？
各位同事，我相信大家都已經收到咧，政府喺。
誒。
呢一兩日咧係發出咗佢哋嘅回覆啦，就住我哋上次嘅會議，九月十五號個會議所提出嘅一啲關注嘅事項咧。
同埋有一啲政誒有一啲所謂團體啦，佢哋喺會議上面所提出嘅一啲意見咧，畀咗個書書面嘅回答畀我哋㗎啦。
噉我哋今日咧就會就住呢一份嘅文件咧。
一陣間都會請政府咧，係。
誒，逐日同我哋講解嘅。
我喺度歡迎咧財經事務及服務局嘅首席助理秘書長。
何國珊小姐同埋。
誒證監會。
誒有幾位同事出席嘅嚇，誒有施捷宏先生、楊以正先生。
同埋咧就啊，仲有就係石志輝先生，同埋趙嘉麗。
女士嘅。
仲有就係處理高級助理法律組議專員啊！
劉雪清女士，啊，歡迎咁多位。
誒，我哋就先請政府咧，係就住嗰份文件咧。
係做個介紹先啦，好嘛？我相信大家都已經收到啦嚇，呢份文件就係C B一。
一二七四零二號嘅文件。
係啊！多謝主席。誒，我哋個文件咧，其實主要都係再述翻我哋上一次會議誒主要討論嘅事項。噉我哋畀一啲誒誒跟進嘅資料啦。咁上一次其實會議其實誒討論比較集中喺兩個議題，我都希望借今日嗰個機會再同啊誒委員可以解釋一下啦。咁其中一項。
咧就係講究竟我哋今次呢個建議做同唔做有咩好處啊？噉樣咁誒，我都其實我哋喺文件咧第五至到第八段咧都畀咗啲資料。噉我都希望喺度誒可以強調啦。其實今次嘅建議咧，我哋係誒畀誒證監會一個非常之有限度嘅新增權力嘅。
意思咧，即係如果呢個香港以外地方嘅規管者，佢要求誒為咗監管目的嘅資料係證監會本身冇嘅時候咧，先至需要採取啊行使呢個權力嘅。咁而特別咧係其中一個條件，點樣先可以誒證監會提供呢個協助咧？就係只有向同時由證監會。
同埋嗰個誒規管者監管嘅持牌法團索取資料，換言之咧，其實證監會好多時候咧，為咗自己嘅監管目的咧，其實好大機會咧，可能其實佢已經有依啲被要求嘅資料，所以係唔需要再向依啲持牌法團另外再索取依啲資料嘅。
咁但係始終嚟講咧，喺個誒法律上咧，證監會始終佢嘅權限就少咗呢一塊啊，所以令到佢咧唔可以能夠同規管者訂立其他誒香港海外地方嘅規管者啦，訂立相互嘅監管協助安排，變咗係誒香港證監會喺佢有需嘅時候咧，唔可。
可以同呢個香港以外地方嘅規管者索取啲資料，用嚟監察香港嘅啊，譬如金融穩定啦，或者確保啊持牌法團嘅規合規嘅。咁另一方面咧，而家好多海外嘅地方咧都誒要求咧誒加強誒同誒證監會嗰個監管協作咧，先至可以容許譬如香港嘅金融。
業進入海外市場嘅，咁誒依啲就係因為，所以我哋今次咧就建議，希望可以畀誒證監會依啲有限度嘅新增權力嘅。
另一個上一次會議比較多討論嘅議題咧，就係誒講我哋緊今次嗰個誒建議嗰個誒機制同其他資料交換機制個法律級框架個比較。噉我哋喺明文件嘅第十至到十七段咧，亦都畀咗啲進一步嘅資料。咁誒簡單嚟講咧，其實我諗我哋睇過所有誒關譬如税務。
資料交換安排啊，同埋相互法律協助安排，同我哋今次建議嗰個誒機制嘅安排最大嘅分別，其實就係其如果嗰幾個交換嘅安誒資料交換安排咧，都係政府同埋其他政府定立，而係具法律約束力嘅協議。而依啲協議咧，因為係具法律誒約。
速力啦，所以要喺香港有依個法律效力嘅時候咧，必須透過定立誒依個附屬法例。
但係咧，就證券市場監管嚟講咧，監管合作咧，依啲通常咧都係透過以量解備忘錄嘅形式，而係同埋喺證券業規管者而唔係政府之間定立嘅，而且佢本身亦都唔具依個法律嘅約束力，亦都明文規定咧係需要受到當地法律所限。
制嘅，所以其實證監會係根本咧係冇呢個空間去定立具法律約束力嘅量解備忘錄，亦都因為係本來呢個誒備忘錄都唔係具約誒法律約束力，所以睇唔到理由咧係需要定立呢個附屬法例嘅。咁另一個誒誒考慮嘅地方咧，就係其實譬如誒舉例咧。
呢個移交逃犯同埋刑事事宜相互法律協助，佢哋立法嘅原意主要咧係為咗定定需要政府行使更加全面嘅權力，誒，亦包括一啲強制嘅措施嘅安排。咁但係相反嚟講咧，我哋今次嗰個建議咧，其實只係畀證監會一啲非強制性嘅權力。
係可以應等佢哋可以應香港以外地方嘅規管者提出嘅要求，提供有限度嘅監管協助。
噉，我哋亦都希望強調咧，證監會今次咧，我哋並唔會畀佢可以賦誒賦權啊，畀佢哋進入任何法團嘅處所嘅。咁事實上咧，為咗提高透明度啦，證監會本來亦都係需要根據法例現有嘅一百第一百八十六誒誒誒第五款啦嘅規定，喺欠報刊登同。
同佢定立咗監管亮解備忘錄嘅香港以外地方嘅規管者嘅名稱嘅。另外咧，證監會咧亦都會將佢喺個網站嗰度咧登載咧已簽署嘅監管亮解備忘錄嘅文本。咁再為咗誒我哋理解咧，委員啦，可能有啲誒業界關注啦，其實誒證監會喺上一次。
嘅會議上邊咧，誒都承諾啦，佢哋會定期同公眾啦、立法會啦咁誒交代有關嘅誒工作啦，喺個誒誒監管協助方面啦，噉佢哋亦都會同業界加強溝通，誒瞭解佢哋嘅關注㗎。咁主席，我嘅簡簡介係噉。
唔該曬，阿張華峯議員有問題係咪？啊，多謝主席。
就我哋立法會法律事務部向證監委查詢有關跨境實地視察嘅問題咧，就我有幾點想啊證監委澄清一下嘅。
喺C B括號一個文件之中附件嘅第四條。
有關跨境實地視察。
喺註解大陸段嘅細字之中咧，正襟為指有一啲司法管係根據當地嘅法律。
有跨境權力喺其他嘅司法管轄區進行實地嘅時測，我想問一問。
有乜有邊度嘅司法管轄區有呢種特別嘅權力？
香港是否有相關嘅條例允許佢允許其他地方監管者嚟香港實地嘅視察咧？唔該。
好啊！阿張源問嘅咧就係上一次嘅文件啦。噉我想知道一下就係對於今次剛才阿何小姐介紹嘅嗰個文件咧，大家有冇咩問題先？我有嘅，不過會唔會等我問？
如果係你有啦，我想話先處咗你嗰個先啦，好嘛？阿張議員一陣間先答你啦，好唔好？啊，OK。因為誒，我哋一陣間亦都會討論到你剛才提出嘅嗰個問題嘅，好嘛？啊，馴政界議員。好。
多謝主席。就第九段嗰度咧，關於歐盟成員啦，就你列咗三個國家，德國、荷蘭同埋英國。我想問咧，因為我唔知道，我可能一定係睇得唔夠詳細啦，就。
美國係點做㗎？
即係我知你文件都冇交代歐國係係咩？
美國係點做係咪？
我另外回答。
師生係嘛？
Thank you very much for the question. I actually happened to be in Washington and the United States, Washington and New York last week, and I discussed this very point with the regulatory commissions there. There, my understanding from my discussions with the reg.
監察委員會，美國的監察委員會，他們的傳喚權力是如此廣泛。
that they do not need a specific enabling piece of legislation to provide for the mechanisms which are envisaged by the bill. This appears to contrast with the European, including the United Kingdom, Singapore and Australian.
legal status where a specific power has been granted by the legislatures there to enable the provision. Since our analysis, unlike the United States, is that we don't have a general power, we believe that this that this
This power needs to be enabled, and hence, hence the proposal under the bill.
誒，佢唔需要一個法例，但係佢哋。
佢哋。
佢哋操作嘅時候會係點咧？佢哋都係咪會同誒其他國家簽M O U？只不過佢哋嘅監管機構係唔需要有即係額外嘅權力咁解係嘛？咁但係佢哋嘅M O U會唔會受任何嘅制約噉嘅？
知先啦。
Mr. Sin in in.
There's an important context to to make because of course we actually haven't entered into an MOU to provide for this power yet.
How about you know United States versus other European countries?
versus other, well, the the and this is where it's it's worth.
嗯。
noting that the original catalyst for this particular proposal came out of the United out of Europe.
The catalyst was an ability for Hong Kong private funds.
要market their funds into Europe, the European regulators and the European countries required of Hong Kong.
一個 Memorandum of Understanding， that provided for the power that we are seeking。
那係原嚟嘅催化劑。
在 addition to that original catalyst is a recognition that this power is very beneficial for broad global supervisory cooperation across across across borders and boundaries.
但係，我諗最best response我can make to your question，係，就係，而家，MOUs被requested， of us out of Europe。
有個特定 wish， for this power， and that specific。
wish and those MOUs are directly related.
to market access by Hong Kong firms, which would not ordinarily be granted to those Hong Kong firms.
但 for the existence of these M O U s, and secondly, it will then also provide, we believe, enhanced supervisory cooperation across borders, which is important given the global nature.
of global nature of of markets and many financial intermediaries, not all financial intermediaries. So at this stage, the bulk of the interest in the activity is coming from Europe. We are in discussions with the United States about MOUs, but up until
The point in time that we have, hopefully, have the power, we're not really in a position to to to go much further than we are today when it comes to negotiating MOUs.
我。
其他同事冇問題啦，係咪？
嗱，如果冇問題嘅話咧，我哋就誒呢份文件咧就。
支持政府嗰個。
情況啊，咁誒。
張華鋒議員咧，剛才都提到。
誒有個問題啦嚇。
噉啊！
誒何小姐，你有冇咩嘅回應？係誒，多謝主席。誒，其實頭先阿張議員誒講問題咧，誒，我哋今朝其實喺我哋回應誒法律顧問誒提出嘅問題，我哋今朝誒畀咗一份文件畀議誒畀委員嘅，咁誒其誒誒希望委員都收到啦。噉我哋裏邊誒其實都。
提過嘅咁誒，其實某一啲香港以外地方嘅主管當局啦，即係譬如誒，例如係美國啦，佢哋咧係可以根據當地嘅法律咧係有依個跨境嘅權力。咁所以咧，其實佢哋誒係喺誒對於佢哋管轄範圍之內，或者已經接受佢管轄嘅實體，譬如啦嗰個母公司喺香。
港以外地方係受規管嘅子公司咧，可以進行呢個跨境啊實地視察嘅。咁所以其實嚟講咧，就唔佢哋呢啲噉嘅公司咧，係唔會受到香港法例或者證監會誒佢誒所佢唔可以逼佢哋要接受呢個跨境誒嘅誒實地視察嘅。咁
咁或者我揾啊證監會嘅同事啊進一步解釋。
I'd be delighted to add, if I may, Mr. Chairman. In response to Mr. Chung's question, I would like to also clarify that cross-border on-site visits are not caught by the proposed bill. This is a separate, existing supervisory cooperation mechanism which is governed.
Governed by MOU arrangements that we have, and has been mentioned, the United States is a particularly good example of a jurisdiction who have regulatory bodies who do conduct on-site visits across borders, including in Hong.
Hong Kong, and they do notify us. There are also examples of European regulators coming to Hong Kong and again conducting on-site visits here. But I do want to just again emphasise that the cross-border on-site visits is an existing, pre-existing supervisory.
工具，which is very commonly used. The United States will visit. I know, for instance, the United Kingdom. The United Kingdom will visit the United States. Regulators operating across borders, particularly in a Western Hemisphere sense, is is is is.
是個existing precedent，both in the Western Hemisphere and here in Hong Kong.
啊，張員，我想就呢個條例係唔係只係咧香港嘅公司，佢冇公司喺美國註冊，自有權咧去誒接受呢個跨境實地嗰個視察。如果本身喺香港註冊或者係海外其他地方註冊，呢條條例係唔適用嘅。
係唔受呢條條例嘅規限嘅咧？
我。
支持王先生。
just thank you, Mr. Truong. Just to clarify the proposed bill before the the council.
它只關聯到持牌公司，無論是受規管於第二個管轄區，或者有個相關公司受規管於第二個管轄區。所以，如果我理解這個問題正確，我認為答案是。
只係，只
separate and existing to the current proposal, our understanding of on-site visits from a foreign regulator comes about because
The Hong Kong licensed corporation.
has submitted to the jurisdiction of that third.
country。
或，有某種形式的 consolidate 監督，那來自於第三個國家。
那係我哋嘅理解，點樣跨境現場訪問會運作。
and I think the conclusion.
從那atement會 be， if there is no supervisory or regulated connection。
到一第三國。
then a on-site visit would be inappropriate and would not occur. It only occurs when there has been a submission.
到那第三國管轄權，但係，我再次強調，跨國境內視察並不在本法案的範疇內，我所講述和解釋的，是關於現有的監督工具。
清楚啦嘛。
好啊，梁繼昌議員。
Thank you, Mr. Chairman. I just want to follow up on the cross-border on-site visits arrangement. It does seem to me that under paragraph C of the government's answer.
The cross-border visit arrangement are purely an arrangement between the foreign regulator and the regulated entity. The FFC normally would just stand back and let those you know arrangement happen.
但，我 just wondering if the if the regulated entity in Hong Kong, for some reasons, resists that you know request for onsite visit.
has such incident happened before, and if such incident happens, what
under the current arrangement or the MOUs signed by the SFC, would SFC be involved in such scenario?
Thank you for the question, Mr. Long. I am not aware of any licensed corporation in Hong Kong that has refused an on-site visit. It's probably opportune for me to say that they're not common either. They don't occur frequently. When they do occur,
They are usually, from our understanding, because you are absolutely correct. We do not have any direct involvement, nor do we support or supplement those cross-border on-site visits ourselves. In the event that there was a refusal.
由一個有執照的公司提交到一個海外現場訪問，那會是兩方之間的事，即係海外的監管機構。
And the licensed corporation and would not ordinarily involve us, and we would not insert ourselves into into such a discussion.
兩個章魚，冇問題。O K O K。
咁基本上咧，就政府都回應咗我哋法律顧問嘅一啲提問啦嚇。
大家同事如果冇問題嘅話咧，
噉我哋今日咧就。
誒，下一個階段，我哋要進入咧呢個逐條審議嘅工作㗎啦。
我哋請誒。
秘書長咧就係。
帶領我哋嚇逐條噉樣去審議。係誒，多謝主席。係噉，我建議委員咧都誒可以睇翻誒秘書處誒準備咗嗰個標明文本啦。
噉我哋條例草案嘅第二步咧，主要咧就係誒誒修訂現有嘅條例啦，去免除持牌代表持有印刷本牌照嘅需要。誒，但係咧，持牌法團同埋註冊機構咧，需要佢喺喺佢嘅主要營業地點展示印刷本牌照嘅現行規定咧，係維。
恆持不變嘅。
咁所以咧，其實啊，標明文本嘅第一至到第六頁咧，其實主要咧都係為咗反映呢個建議咧。我哋咧建議修訂條例嘅第一六一七條啦，加入條文，使到證監會咧係需要向發牌嘅法團咧發出呢個印刷本嘅牌照㗎。
咁另外第七至到第十二頁咧，主要都係修訂翻條例嘅第一百二十至一百廿一頁啦，反映證監會咧係無需要再向代誒呢個持牌代表發給呢個印刷本牌照，而改係以書面通知咧去申請人嘅。
噉我哋亦都同時新增一個條文啦，指明證監會喺草案實施之前發畀持牌代表嘅印刷本牌照咧，將唔會再具有顯示某某名個人獲發牌嘅效力㗎。
咁由於證監會咧，亦都唔會再向呢個持牌代表發批啊發出呢個印刷本牌照啦，所以草案咧就會廢除有關持牌代表嘅牌照被撤銷之後需要交還牌照同埋咧啊相關罰則嘅條文嘅。
咁去到標明文本嘅第十三頁啦，呢個咧主要係一個誒，主要係一個技術性嘅修訂嘅啫，反映條例第一百二十二條向持牌代表批准遞屬轉移嘅情況之下咧，誒並冇對印刷本牌照嘅提述㗎。
好啊！啊，到呢度為止，大家同事有冇咩問題？善總嘉議。
你個目的有冇咩關係嘅？
誒，因為今次我哋依個條例草案咧，最主要特誒頭先我哋傾過嗰個關於政誒證監會嗰個監管誒合作啦，但係其餘咧，我哋都有一啲誒誒比較輕微嘅修訂，我哋都擺咗喺依個條例草案裏邊。咁其實喺我哋嗰個立法會誒個誒嗰個natural brief嗰個誒文件摘要咧，我哋都有提述嘅。
咁呢個第二部分咧，就係一個其中嘅一個誒比較誒簡單嘅修訂嚟嘅。
有冇其他問題？我哋繼續啦，好嗎？
係，多謝主席。咁誒。
去到誒第十五頁啦，都係一個技術性修訂啦，廢除而家條例第一百二十三條有關持牌代表終止為其主事人行事之後交還牌照同埋相關罰則嘅條文嘅。
第十六至到第十七頁咧，同樣係一個技術性修訂嚟嘅，修改咧一百二十四條有關牌照副本嘅條文啦，同埋一百二十七條有關更改持牌人獲發牌獲或者獲註冊嘅受規管活動嘅條文，主要都係要表達咧，而誒證監會咧只會係向持牌法團發出。
印冊本牌照，同埋向註冊機構發出註冊證明書嘅。
咁去到第廿二頁啦，咁其實都係喺嗰個誒附表加入一個適宜嘅啫，因為我哋誒加入呢個印刷本牌照嘅誒解釋嘅啫。
係梁繼昌嘅，我想問，我想問一問，點而家其實你？
即係咪冇咗個printer licence，只會係得一個printer licence去點樣樣啊？而同埋你嗰個改動嗰個目的係係咪想慳翻啲錢咧？即係即係我唔知係係點解要改佢啊？我嗱啲簡化手續啊，啲噉嘅嘢嚇啊誒，係多謝主席誒，或者我可以解釋一下啦。咁而家我哋今次嘅建議咧，只係取。
啊免除向持牌發啊持牌代表啊持有印刷本嗰個啊牌照嗰個需要，持牌法團啦或者註冊機構係仍然我哋啊證監會會發出呢個印刷本牌照。咁嗰個目的咧，其實因為好多時候咧，誒誒，其實我哋條例咧只係要求呢個啊持牌法團喺佢嗰個主要營業地。
點掛佢嗰個牌照出嚟，主要係為呢個投誒做呢個投資者保障嘅啫。咁至於嗰個持牌代表，好多時候其實佢哋嗰個牌照都唔會喺嗰個持牌營業地點嗰度整出嚟嘅。噉我哋其實而家證監會嗰個網站裏邊咧，誒都已經寫曬最新嗰個持牌代表、持牌發團嗰個名單㗎啦。咁所以我哋誒做完呢個。
個建議修定之後咧，誒一來咧就希望可以減省誒持牌代表佢嗰個誒可能又要個手續啊，或一個費用啦。咁第二，我哋都會做翻一個誒加強嗰個投資者教育啦，叫邀誒即係同通知佢哋，即係如果第時要睇持牌代表最新資料咧，就會上翻誒證監會官網站嘅。
好。
噉我哋繼續咧。
呃。
跟住嚟咧，誒去到標明文本第廿四頁啦。咁其實佢依度之後咧，係由第二至第四分部咧，都係主要同發牌相關附屬法例嘅修訂嘅啫。咁其實廿四至三十四頁咧，全部都係一啲技術性修訂，全部都係希望反映翻以後證監會咧，只係會向。
向持牌發團發出印冊本牌照，同埋向註冊機構發出啊註冊證明書，依啲相關條文做出修訂嘅啫。
咁接住嚟咧，就係第三十五頁至到第九十八頁。依個誒第二步嘅第五分步咧，其實再有咧就係立法會喺一四年三月通過嘅《二零一四證券及期貨修訂條例》有關呢個監管場外衍生工具誒佢嗰邊嘅附表十一有關個。
度性條文嘅修訂嘅咁而家我哋咧就啊證監會就計劃喺呢個過渡期間咧，就向相關嘅中介人發出特定嘅附表十一印冊本牌照同埋註冊證明書，示明佢哋咧係當作為獲發牌或者獲註冊進行新增或者誒涵蓋範圍擴大咗嘅。
就規管活動嘅，咁呢個誒呢個計誒即係呢個建議咧，都係希望中介人啦可以向呢啲客户咧展示佢哋有一個實物嘅證明書，為提資啊投資者提供更加嘅保障嘅。
咁誒標明文本嘅第四十四至到九十三頁咧，其實都係反映翻頭先誒我哋嗰個建議啦，全部都係一啲技術性修訂，只係係反映呢個誒過渡期間咧，證監會只係會向持牌法團發出呢個印刷本嘅牌照嘅。
噉我哋其實接住落嚟可以去到第九十四頁。
噉我哋就喺呢個誒附表十一啦，就增加咗一個新嘅五A部。咁其實第一咧就係為頭先我哋所提過啦，嗰個附表十一印刷本牌照同埋附表十一註冊證明書提供一個適宜啦。
咁九十四到九十五頁咧，就係表明證監會會喺場外衍生工具市場嘅中介人當作獲發牌或者獲註冊嘅過渡期間咧，同向佢哋發出呢個附表十一印冊誒誒印冊本牌照或者係一個附表十一註冊證明書誒，指明咧。
呢啲中介人咧係當作獲發牌或者註冊進行受規管活動嘅。
至於九十五同九十六頁咧，就誒依個修訂咧，係表明中介人如果被終止佢作當作為持牌或者註冊嘅身份咧，必須咧將呢個印冊本嘅牌照或者註冊證明書咧交翻畀證監會嘅，並咗並定明冇按照規定交還而冇合理辯解嘅罰則。
係，嗯。
如果冇第二部分誒，就係咁多啦。如果條例草案咧，去到第一百頁咧，就係第三步，就係就向香港以外地方規管者提供監管協助而修訂證券及期貨條例嘅啊嘅誒草案啦。咁誒第一百頁到到一百零七頁咧，就係一個技術性修訂。
因為經修訂之後嘅第一百八十六條啦，除咗列明證監會向香港以外地方規管者提供調查協助之外咧，我哋仲加入咗提供監管協助嘅條文，所以我哋咧就建議修訂第一百七十九條，誒將第一百八十六條喺誒嘅提述改為一百八十六一或者二。
條清楚表明咧，依個第一百七十九條只係適用於喺調查協助嘅情況嘅啫。
跟住落嚟咧，就去到一百一十頁。
咁呢個就係條例第一百八十條列明證監會誒喺監管中介人誒同埋嗰個聯係實體可行使嘅監管權力嘅。噉我哋而家建議就加入新嘅第四A款賦權啊獲授權人喺向海香港以外地方嘅規管者。
提供協助嘅情況下咧，要求持牌法團或者佢嘅聯繫法團啦，提供某一啲記錄或者文件，同埋回答某一啲問題嘅。但係我哋對呢個權誒權力咧係作出咗規限，喺呢個第新嘅四A款咧，我哋包括寫明咧，只可以要求取得同呢個受誒受規管活動有。
關嘅資料㗎。
接住，我哋可以去到第一百一十九頁。
有關呢個新增嘅第二A款，呢個二A新二A款咧係規定，證監會只可以喺特定嘅情況下提供監管協助嘅。咁第一咧，提出要求嘅規管機構，執要係執行同證監會相似嘅職能，並並且已經受到足夠嘅保密條文所規限咯。
咁第二咧，請求嘅協助咧，係必須要符合公眾利益嘅。
第三咧，規管機構咧已提供符合新增嘅第二D款嘅書面陳述啦，表明未能夠同埋將唔能夠借任何其他合理地誒方法取得所要求嘅資料，同埋喺冇依啲資料嘅情況下咧，唔能夠同埋將唔夾能將不能夠全面確定喺新。
新增嘅第二B款描述嘅事宜，即係話咧有關持牌法團或者佢嘅聯係法團，會否對其司法管轄誒區喺金融方面嘅穩定構成風險啦？或者依個持牌法團或其有聯係法團。
係咪有遵從提出請求嘅規管者所施行與證券有關嘅法律規定或者規管性規定嘅？
咁另外咧，第四啦，依個規管機構咧係必須已經提供符合新增第二依款嘅書面承諾嘅。咁依個第二依款嘅書面承諾所包含嘅嘢係乜嘢咧？咁誒，其實喺第一百二十一頁啦，標明文本嗰度有寫啦。依個主要係為咗防止進一步。
披露資料或者喺未經授權嘅情況下使用資料嘅噉，所以我哋咧建議咧誒呢個提出請求嘅規管者必須向證監會提交一個書面承諾，表明佢只係會因該項協助請求而從證監會取到嘅資料咧，只係用翻，只係用嚟確定頭先講。
嗰個啦，第二B款所述嘅事宜啦，而唔會喺任何程序中啊使用上述嘅資料㗎。
亦都會將呢啲資料咧列作機密處理，同埋唔會喺未獲證監會同意之下啦，為任何目的而向任何其他人披露呢啲資料啦。如果喺接獲喺法律上可強制執行有關披露任何資料嘅要求，就會喺合理、咁切實可行嘅範圍裏邊，盡快通知。
證監會啦，採取嘅所可誒所有可用嘅適當措施，協助將呢啲資料保密嘅。
咁並且佢依個喺依個書面承諾咧，亦都要講明佢咧會志在誒會確保咧依啲資料保密嘅任何行動同埋程序中咧係會同證監會合作嘅。
阿同事有冇問題啊？
冇問題。
法律顧問有冇嘅咧？法律顧問。
個問題咧就想跟進翻咧，即係呢個新家嘅二。
誒喺呢個嘅E嘅D咧，就喺嗰個嘅係。
羅馬數字二嘅第二款嗰度啦，噉就所講咧就話係採取所有可用嘅釋放措施，咁咧就以協助咧將該等資料保密嘅。噉我就想知道，如果嗰個有關嘅當局咧，佢係冇誒喺李括所提及嘅，即係話誒宣示法律嘅豁免權啦，或者係法律特權嘅時候。
咁仲有咩其他嘅措施咧？可唔可以即係喺呢度澄清翻咧？即係如果佢嗰個制度係同香港係有所出入嘅時候，誒呢個證監誒或者係即係政府當局係會點樣做去保障翻咧？
係，係主席誒。我諗我哋嘅呢個條文裏邊咧，其實都寫咗咧，佢括弧裏邊係包括，但不限於啦。咁所以其實誒，亦都係寫明可以有其他嘅誒方法啦，即係不限於嗰個所謂宣示法律誒豁免權同法律特權，或者長情我誒請證監會啊，Mr. Young。
我。
先生。
唔，唔，我其實冇任何嘢可以加到嗰度。我，
嗯。
嗱，我哋再repeat一次畀佢，即係除咗啊嚇。
我哋顧問，你再講一次啦嘛，因為佢佢。
聽唔到個翻譯啊，係啦。
最近去。
It is stated in the section 186(2e) and then in the paragraph d subsection in the paragraph two.
佢哋話，嗰啲。
The written undertaking referred to in subsection two A B must be to the effect that the authority or the regulatory organisations.
Well, on receiving a demand legally enforceable under the laws of the jurisdiction of the authority or regulatory organisation for the disclosure of any of the information, assist in preserving the confidentiality of the information by taking all the appropriate measures as may be available.
My question is, what if the other jurisdictions they does not have such legal measures, such as the legal exemptions or the privileges under that law of the jurisdictions? What other measures will be available to to protect the licensed corporations? All right, thank you. And didn't didn't get that the first time round. Yes. I mean, we we anticipate
I repeat that most other jurisdictions that we will be dealing with will have equivalents to public interest immunity or something along those lines. Most of the common law jurisdictions, the US and UK and other jurisdictions will have something similar to that. To the extent that they don't have PII, they may well have other protections.
I mean, it will be jurisdiction specific, and we would work with the the local regulator to see what possible legal avenues were available and pursue them as as best we can.
不如噉。
Okay, but if these measures they are not equivalent to that of the Hong Kong say for example the LPP or the right against the self-incriminations, but
嗯。
Would you say that these protections are adequate?
我哋依家。
Well, I mean, as I say, most most of the jurisdictions that we would be dealing with, US in Europe as well, they they would have legal professional privilege, they would have public interest immunity, they would have equivalent. And they may not be exact, but they will be very very similar. Certainly, all common law jurisdictions will have that.
But I mean, there may be alternative protections available as well. It really is. It's I mean, it's impossible to be prescriptive. It will depend on the jurisdiction.
O.K.嚇，選委嘉怡，嗱，主席，我慢慢問啊，容許我，誒，我想睇翻第一一九頁同一二零頁。
嗰個。
新增嘅二大嘅二A。
下面嘅括弧細A。
證監會認為。
一該當局話機構符合五括弧A B所提述嘅，噉係咪即係五括弧A B即係係一二四嗰個A B啊？係咪即即係中文嘅一二四頁嗰個A B？
李主席，O.K.，係好嗱。咁如果係咁咧，我嘅問題就問咧。
公眾會唔會知道？
證監會覺得邊一啲機構係A同B符合嘅，即係會唔會有一個？
即係附表或者係任何嘅公開嘅文件，知道咧係公眾可以瞭解到究竟乜嘢嘅監管機構咧係證監會係認為符合相關嘅規定。
何主席係多謝主席。誒嗱，頭先啊，如果誒，其實如果證監會佢同任何一個誒規管者簽訂咗呢啲誒亮解備忘錄咧，佢哋根據法例要求咧，都要將呢個誒地方嗰個規管者咧係需要刊登欠報嘅。咁或者誒，我睇下。
Mr. Shipton有冇嘢補充下？哦，Mr. Shipton，Yes. So the we will firstly gazette the names of the regulators with whom we enter into supervisory cooperation arrangements.
And then in the ordinary course, we would also publish those MOU arrangements, so that it would be very clear to the public and all interested parties the scope and extent to which we have entered into supervisory cooperation arrangements with different regulators. And I must stress.
That there will be differences on this whole point of reciprocity, which we've consistently sort of confirmed. That only where there is a reciprocal ability to enter into such an arrangement as envisaged by the bill, and there is a reciprocal desire to enter into
such arrangements, including for instance granting market access, only then will we enter into it. This is a this is a discretionary power as far as we are concerned. It is not a mandatory power, and it is entirely possible that many MOU arrange or not.
Let me rephrase it. It's entirely possible that not not all MOU arrangements that we enter into with other jurisdictions would include provisions envisaged by this bill. That said, we do expect a significant degree of interest from the Western Hemisphere and desire to enter into MOU.
arrangements, including provisions as envisaged by the bill that we're discussing.
誒，如果噉，我再問多個問題就係：，咁公眾係咪將來會好容易查閲到？嗱，因為你你哋同唔同，我估證監將來可能都會同唔同嘅機構，除咗簽呢啲交換資料協議之外。
都可能簽其他嘅，冇咗都唔出嘅。
咁公眾有冇一個好簡單嘅？
地方附表，一眼睇曬，你係可以用根據呢一條新增嘅呢條條款行使嘅權利㗎。
係啊啊，多謝主席，多謝啊善員。誒，佢哋嘅誒所有頭誒個文M O U個文本咧，都會喺個網上喺證監會個網址上邊。噉佢有個特定有一刻噉，你click入去咧，就應該會冚唪唥會列舉曬出嚟㗎。
我知，但係公眾，我知啦。呢個係一個你嗱，呢個係透透明嘅。公眾係一個可以查完曬每個M O U嘅文件，係呢個係好啊，我讚賞。但係會唔會一個簡易嘅方法都可以容許到畀誒公眾知道有邊幾個地區或者國家誒政監門？
會會係根據呢一條條款行使交換資料嘅權利嘅。
the the exchange of information arrangements will invariably differ from different jurisdictions to different jurisdictions.
所以。
The level of transparency which we believe is appropriate is to make available all of the MOU arrangements that we enter into. Of course, subject to very rare requests, which I'm actually not aware of any to date.
That would
forbid or disallow us to publish those things.
所以，Putting that very rare and unlikely event to one side.
We will publish the full text of each supervisory MOU arrangement.
And it will be very clear inside those MOU arrangements that there will be provisions relating to the exchange of information. So it would be very it would be very clear to interested parties to search and readily obtain an understanding as to whether an arrangement.
with a particular jurisdiction includes the incremental power that is envisaged by this bill. I also know, because it's been said to me already, that many legal advisers watch very closely the MOU arrangements between different jurisdictions.
因為他們在諮詢客户，許多他們，許多他們，運作跨境，和完全意識和完全欣賞，的可能，的資訊交換，即使在現有的措施，目前。
好，同事冇其他問題啊嘛。
上官宇，我想問二師嗰度咧。
即係一二一頁二C嗰度咧。
嗱，你話為實施二第二B款而指明的法團，是符合以下説明的法團。
誒跟住就括號A同B啦，屬上述主管當局或規管。
機構所管轄的及所屬所持牌法團，或屬持牌法團的有聯繫法團。
可唔可以具體啲講咩個聯係法團啊？
係啊，多謝主席。誒，意思A同B咧係兩個之間係有個及字啦，咁所以其實最誒一一定要係依個誒所謂誒依個持牌法團一定係同要求資料嗰個主管當局或者規管誒誒機構係所規管，依個係一定要嘅啦。咁第二咧就係。
同時間喺個B嗰度，除咗受到嗰個要求資料嗰個規管機構規管，亦都要係證監會嘅持牌法團。咁呢個係第一款啦。第二款就係如果佢係二C A屬係依個要求資料嘅法團規管，誒嘅機構規管，或者佢係一個屬持牌。
牌法團嘅有聯係法團，咁呢個誒就主要就係講，如果即係呢個喺持牌法團佢誒呢個聯係法團，佢未必係證監會誒所規管，但係佢係一個證監會所規管持牌法團嘅有聯係法團啦。咁而佢呢個同時間亦都要係需要嗰個。
誒剷除資料嗰個誒海外機構所規管嘅。
嗱，我我知啊，嗱。
誒二二大司括胡世B嗰個咧，就係證監會嘅法團，或屬或持牌法團。
的有聯繫法團，O.K.嗱，縮詞牌法團咧就明白啦，你有佢嘅資料啦。但係縮詞牌法團嘅有聯繫法團咧，咁政監會又會會有佢嘅資料嘅咩？
好，主席。
我唔識讀。
As I believe this is submitted in written papers, but the words related corporation is defined under the ordinance, under the Securities and Futures Ordinance, and essentially it refers to a holding company, a subsidiary, a subsidiary of the same holding company.
And the thresholds are composition of control of the composition of the board, control of half the voting rights, or holding half of issued capital. That's a well established and recognised definition of related corporations. But I think, Mr Sinn, you're also.
回應到的fact， as to
Pre or in advance of transparency of what companies constitute a related corporation, that that would be.
outside of our scope because at any given time there could be any number of different related corporations existing overseas and of course again the scope must be that that related.
company or related corporation has to be regulated overseas for it to fall within the boundaries of the of the provision proposed by the bill.
嗱，呢個咧，我覺得係有少少。
我唔知咪應該個問題去講啊！你客觀上咧，頭先啊，Mr。
係咯。
Shipton所講咧，你最初個描述咧，咩字話有幾多個誒咩董事啊，等等嗰啲咧？
嗰個嘅定義咧，就係窄好多。
但係，如果你用一個表面嘅字眼咧，用得上癮。
即係common sense，常人嘅理解有聯係法團咧，就點咧？喂，坐時排嘅法團，佢嘅。
佢加加入對手，加入對手都可以係呢一個有關聯嘅有聯係嘅花團嚟。呢個呢個，我諗係有特定嘅解釋嘅。誒係啊，主席，其實我哋喺誒法例裏誒，即係任呢個誒期貨誒券證券及期貨條例嗰個附表嘅第一部第三條，已經將有聯係花團。
個定義寫咗落去嘅，咁一定係根據個法例，係現喺現有法例嚟嘅嚇。我知可唔可以？誒。
即我要，我要搞清楚個谷係咪真係好闊？
係，一係攞個SFO出嚟，等我哋睇清咗第幾。有啊，有啊，有。
有。
我哋法律部門有啊，我哋嗰啲。
咪或者法律顧問讀一讀啊，好嘛？誒，讀一讀咪得咯。
個definition到嗰度。
就係呢個嘅。啊，船洞街議員，係，唔好意思。
有，得睇啊！
O.K.英語都冇問題，我估我都識嘅。
中英都有我哋呢度啊。
呢個。
或者我哋法律顧問讀一次啦，因為我相信好多誒，即係聽眾或者觀眾佢哋都都想知道嘅。就有聯係法團嘅提述啦嚇喺誒證監嘅條例而言咧，如果多於一個法團，而其中一個一是其餘法團嘅控權公司啦，二啦係其餘法團嘅附屬公司，或者係三。
係，其餘法團所屬嘅控誒控權公司嘅附屬公司，咁呢啲法團咧就視為彼此的有聯繫法團。
而B咧就係話：如果個人咧，如果係控制一個或者多一個發團嘅董事局嘅組成，或者二啦，控制一個或者多過一個發團喺成員大會上嘅個半數控誒嘅投票權啦，又或者三持有一個或者多於一個發團嘅個半數已經發行嘅股本，咁咧嘅話咧，則第一二三節咧提述。
嘅每一個法團同埋其一嘅每一個誒附屬公司咧，都會視為彼此有聯係嘅法團。咁其實呢一個所謂有聯係法團，就已經喺呢一個嘅誒第三款入邊咧，就有個界定㗎啦。
啊，主席，我哋誒補充一句，頭先誒法律顧問提述嗰個個人就喺同我哋嗰個條例草案就未必就有關，因為我哋主要都係講一個誒法團。
上街完仲有冇問題？有，但係仲冇。
跟住落先啦，啊主席。
好啊，咁誒。
嗯。
何小姐，我哋繼續啊嘛。
繼續落去咧，就去到第一百二十三頁啦。
一百二十三頁啦，主要係將第一百八十六條裏邊有關證監會提供嘅調查協助嘅保障，例如誒，譬如對誒係需要嗰個誒協助係需要合乎公眾利益啊，對方嗰個誒規管機構係需要受到保密條文嘅規限，呢啲嘅保障咧，伸延到去監。
監管協助嘅。
呢個，嗯。
我想問多個問題，即係比較整體睇。
收到呢啲嘅請求之後，提供協助咧，會唔會？
即係隨即係會，你會唔會通知嗰個受影響嘅人士啊？
係誒，主席誒，因為其實今次我哋嗰個建議就係，如果證監會冇手頭冇嗰個被要求嗰個資料咧，就係令到誒證監會有權向嗰個持牌法團，即係合誒，關於個符合嗰個條件嘅持牌法團直接攞嗰啲資料，所以自然而然咧係會一定要通知佢，然後問佢直接攞嗰啲資料。知，但係如果有。
如果有咧，其實根據現有法例咧，誒係已經有條文可以約誒等證監會畀依個資料畀對方嘅。
即係唔會通知嘅。
好，我想問咧喺現有而家新建議裏邊咧。
收到嗰個。
即係收到你要求之後咧，我可唔可以反對？
我認為你唔合當地畀佢，有冇得打官司？
其實誒變，如如果佢有誒呢個合理嘅辯解咧，誒證監會係會考慮嘅。咁呢個條文裏邊現有條文，其實都已經有㗎啦。
咩過合唔係？我知合理有範圍㗎嘛嚇，唔係我知合理辯解啫，但係。
你證監會考慮啫，我我我而家唔滿意你證監會決定，我有冇得上訴？係咪要去入邊啊？咩賽邊路嗰度嘅？
Mr. Shipton。
Thank you for the question. There are a number of potential grounds, potential grounds for having a reasonable excuse, including, for instance, the right against self-incrimination. There is also grounds for legal professional privilege.
And we would be open to receiving whatever grounds a licensed corporation may present to us in response to a request.
任何 request for information， that is envisaged by this bill will be very clearly identifiable to the licensed corporation， because we will be mentioning the sections。
and because we mention the sections and the subsections that we are seeking the information under, that will then give notice to the licensed corporation that this information is in relation is being requested by a overseas or non-Hong Kong regulator, and then of course the
是現有的規定，即係一個申請，或者係一個要求，唔要遵守這個資訊要求，有合理的原因可以得到批准。當然，任何時候，任何決定，包括這個決定。
此特別 circumstance is judicially reviewable.
除咗啊，風雨啊，除咗蒸餾之外，即係traditional之外咧，會唔會有啲？
上訴委唔會可以上訴嘅，淨係呢？
喺而家我哋嘅條文建制建建議下面。
no, there would not be any separate appeal mechanisms.
We believe that because of the multiple safeguards, including the undertakings which we'll come on to in a minute.
that there are a range of inbuilt protections that protect the interests of the licensed corporation. Remembering that this provision only relates to licensed corporations, it does not apply to individuals.
所以，assuming that those provisions and protections are adhered to, and also given.
That it is very well established.
And well recognised by corporations operating across borders and across markets, that there is exchange of information for supervisory purposes.
which is separate to enforcement purposes.
given that this is a well-established exchange of information mechanism.
already， we do not believe that an appeal mechanism in addition to the existing rights to judicially review any decision by the commission is necessary or needed.
係。
主席，即係我唔知有冇記錯啦。頭先錢長吉議員所提嘅問題咧，我記得我之前已經問過。嗰個問題就係證監會如果向其他監管機構提供本地券商嘅資料咧，證監會會唔會通知該券商？咁證監會嘅答覆係會嘅。但係頭先我。
我聽到咧就係話，如果賬單已經有手上已經有個建商嘅資料，就無需再通知個建商。呢個係唔係即係我想確定一下啫？
好，Mrs. Shipton。
即即，如果佢有資料，佢就唔需要通知。咁呢個係咪即對嗰個被調查嘅人都係有啲等等證監啊司志宏先生答你，再答一次。That that is correct. Although would Mr. Chan make one clarification, is that this is not relating to an investigation.
The information exchanges that take place as under the existing arrangements, and the distinction is between existing arrangements, are well established. That there is an ability, provided that the gateways are met and there are protections.
such as it is in the best interest and expedient for the public.
It is not a unnecessary drain on resources on the Commission. That there would not there would not be a notification to the licensed corporation in relation to supervisor exchange of information when that information is already on hand. There is a distinction to be made.
with the proposal before the legislative council， and that is when we do not have information to hand。
and that is when we would by
force of the requesting letter， put the licence corporation on notice that the information being requested is for the purposes of a non-Hong Kong regulator. I hope this distinction is clear.
誒主席，我想問一問，交換資料同埋調查要需要嘅資料有咩分別咧？你交換資料分分鐘去變成被調查嘅資料嚟嘅喎，所以交換資料同埋調查資料有咩分別？因為頭先講嘅咧就係係有分別嘅，有啲啊要通知嗰個被。
調曬有啲人冇嘅，咁所以我想清楚交換資料同埋調曬資料有咩分別？
哦。
市集網線啊！
again the informa all of the MOU arrangements that and information exchange arrangements we have when it comes to supervisory cooperation we exchange information with our supervisory counterparts under the arrangement via the MOUs that this is for supervisory
purposes only, and that is the current protocol. If there are to be, if information is to be, wish to be used by another regulator for enforcement purposes, then the existing arrangements and protocols would deem it necessary that a separate information request.
be submitted via the enforcement MOU arrangements. That would that would then govern that information exchange and the use of that information via the non-Hong Kong regulator.
清楚，全座嘉義主席，我對證監第二B嗰度咧，我仲係有啲問題嘅。
誒，即係批中文嘅一二零啊，第二大B嗰度咧。
你講，你話提唔提供協助咧，就係視乎A細A嗰度咧，就話是否對上述主管當局。
或規管機構嘅司法管轄區就係金融穩方面嘅穩定性構成風險，或者係或是否可能影響該區嘅？
誒金融嘅穩定性，嗱呢個係好闊嘅，乜都得嘅。
咁但係有冇前提就係，譬如話，喂，嗱，我唔知道你證監會點做啦，有個機構。
佢突然之間嚟問我：香港呢度你哋攞嘢，但係喺佢哋嗰度咧，根本我個機構係冇做生意嘅，冇嘅，冇任何嘅業務嘅。咁其實係咪？但係。
但係噉樣樣，你。
即係如果佢申請攞牌照，你問下呢個機構，噉我又唔同啦。即係有有個香港機構，我走去譬如話德國或者係誒英國開開分店，噉我申請，噉你嚟問我攞資料咁唔出奇。但係如果我又冇做任何嘢，我淨喺香港做，又唔去嗰度搞，你又冇。但係你當你用A嘅時候咧，呢個就差唔多係萬法朝。
全部都包曬。
你你嘅意思即係話會唔會係限制翻呢間公司根本就冇喺對方呢個當地嗰度係做生意，或者係持牌或者冇業務。如果冇嘅話咧，應該係唔受佢規管嘅。但係因為如果你用A咧，佢冇做，可能啲影響佢嘅喎，係咪先啊？
未睇書啦。誒，主席或者我誒畀個背景先。首先呢個二誒二大B呢個條款咧，其實我哋係聽咗我哋喺公眾諮詢聽咗業界嘅意見之後加上去。噉啊，業界都有提出過咧，話誒嗰個資料究竟誒係咪咩資料都攞咧，會唔會好瑣碎咧？咁噉，所以我哋就。
加上呢個二特二大B度咧，特別規限有關嘅資料咧，其實必須要係外嚟睇下係咪誒影響金融穩定方面啊，或者係咪同合規有關咁？呢個誒新加嗰個所謂保障咧，其實上一次嗰啲團體咧都係表示支持嘅。咁至於嗰個詳細嘅答案。
係，Mr. Shipman，Shipman，即係加嗰個，我先回應一先。加嗰個係縮窄咗冇嘅範圍，梗係一個進步啦。但係加咗之後，仍然係好闊啊！我意思係。
即係我舉一個例子，就係頭先我講個例子，就係如果我喺香港嘅機構根本冇喺被監管，即係即係問你攞資料嗰個地區裏邊，有冇任何業務嘅時候，亦都冇打算去申請任何業務。即係如果我譬如話阿華豐嗰個公司，佢就走去咧個英國攞誒申請攞個牌照，跟住佢就即刻嚟問你攞，噉你？
計可能咁啦，但係佢又冇，佢又冇喺嗰邊做生意，又冇諗住將嗰啲去嗰度申請。我我哋又唔會提供協助畀佢㗎啦。噉係咪係咪你都可以喂？如果佢根據二A，你要畀㗎咯喎？係咪？因為第四係誒，係主席，我諗其實可以睇翻咧誒，因為其實誒條文裏邊仲有第一百零條，我諗依度誒第一百。
十頁啦，所謂要求誒嗰個資料咧，其實仲有一個規限，就係對誒受證監會受規管活動有誒有影響嘅，即係同佢有關嘅。咁所以如果佢根本都係冇冇做任何活動啊，或者誒點樣根本就係唔會跌入去。第一誒一百十頁。你跟住落去。
個意思都係已經講咗嘅啦，即係如果唔喺佢當地嗰度誒有註冊嘅一啲所謂法團咧，根本佢亦都都即係攞唔到啲文件，我哋都唔會畀佢。
唔係唔係意意思，C B係講香港人係註冊法團。
誒嗱，我我再誒講係第一百，首先第一百一十頁啦，係依個係第一百零第新嘅誒第四大A條。
咁呢個就係規定咧，所誒嗰個啲誒要提供嘅資料咧，係對嗰個法持牌法團進行嘅誒任何規管活動有關。咁換言之咧，即係其實如果你頭先嗰個例子，嗰嗰間公司都冇任何活動嘅，咁自然亦都唔會對任何誒誒證監會受規管活動有任何影響。
噉係唔需要提供呢個資料嘅。
呢個係清楚嘅，呢個清楚。
啊，你識食偏？
Thank you. Supplement. I think the example, Mr. Sin, that you use is is the chairman is correct that there would not be a nexus in the in the two jurisdictions in that case. There has to be a regulatory nexus relating to securities or securities compliance or financial stability in.
effect in that second jurisdiction.
And if there is not activities being undertaken, or a registration in that second jurisdiction, then the provisions would not apply.
It's also worth emphasising that there's another provision which we'll come on to in a minute, which requires confirmation from the second country regulator that the information is for the purposes of determining financial stability or compliance with their own regulations. That gives us.
and ability us as in the SFC to go back and question and query the non-Hong Kong regulator to see whether there are sufficient grounds to justify such requests because we are cognizant and aware that we do not want we do not want this provision to be used as a fishing
expedition， and we do not want this provision to be used for unintended purposes. and I know that everybody is in complete agreement in in relation to that. because at the end of the day， this proposal only provides us with a discretion to be able to grant the information. it
does not mandate us to give the information. If we do have concerns or reservations that the information is not for the purposes of financial stability, which is an important subject matter, or the information is not
for the purposes of compliance with securities regulation, there is a final point that I know Miss Ho will come on to in a minute.
which is essentially that.
另一個確認 has to be obtained before we can provide this narrow form of supervisory assistance.
and that is that that second regulator that non-Hong Kong regulator cannot get the information itself.
因為它係非常common。
在existing arrangements in the financial markets globally.
And as I mentioned before, in relation to another matter.
If a group company submits to the regulation.
of another.
regulator， then it is likely to adhere to information requests directly from that regulator.
therefore we believe that in the vast majority of cases where information is required by a non-Hong Kong regulator, they may go direct, and if they can go direct to get that information, then then there's no need to use this provision.
That said, this provision is very important because it is required as an important backstop for market access, because it's required by jurisdictions like the European Union. And secondly, there will be times where it is legitimate.
and appropriate that another regulator wishes to verify or obtain via the SFC information that does relate to either financial stability or adherence to rules in that jurisdiction.
專家議，我仲一個問題，關於畀通唔通知，即係被又唔係調查被誒。
搜尋資料嘅機構。
喺呢個問題上咧，我想問咧，證監會或者啊局長啊啊啊啊啊秘書長咧，就係。
其實可唔可能係法例上規定佢咧？
最後尾嗱，你即係頭先講咧，就係誒佢冇嘅資料，你就一定問佢攞，佢一定知啦。
但係你有嘅時候咧，你就唔使問嘅啦嘛，你就直接畀佢啦嘛。但係唔你畀咗啲乜嘢資料佢，其實係可以誒。
因為呢個唔係一個調查啊嘛，你話一個一個一個一個即係做個案嘅調查啊嘛。
咁可唔可能係你係規定佢係要通知證監通知呢一個受影響嘅人士咧？
即係簡單嚟講，譬如話我哋呢度所講荷蘭定德國噉樣樣，誒。
誒問你某某公司或者券商攞啲資料誒誒誒攞啲資料，嗰個券商你你有嘅資料就畀咗佢啦。但係畀佢同時咧，你又通知翻受啲受唔知咩叫調查，又唔係調查，受受研究啦嚇，受研究嘅機構咧噉。
我書籍。
Mr. Shipton. Mr. Shipton, to confirm, Mr. Sinn, there is there is no provision when it comes.
to exchange supervisor information that is already in our possession, to notify the relevant licensed corporation.
I would stress, though, as a matter of practice, that this is.
well established。
internationally.
and.
The information that is usually requested and usually discussed.
Across different regulators, such as, for instance.
在 supervisory college meetings， which are very well established, very important to global financial stability.
There is discussion between regulators of, in effect, their own regulatory and supervisory assistance.
the information that usually is discussed, and information that is usually exchanged.
Usually relates to, let's call it the the assessment or the risk assessments or the analysis by a regulator of a licensed corporation.
for supervisory purposes.
Rarely, at least in my experience, rarely is there a request for a particular piece of data or trade reference.
again， that is because。
When we are dealing with financial groups that operate across borders,
The foreign or the non-Hong Kong regulator will usually go direct to that group.
itself to seek that particular trade or information data.
what regulators are ordinarily interested in in exchanging, when it comes to this information exchange that you're referring to.
That is the vast in the vast majority of cases, that really comes down to our own confidential assessments.
of licensed corporations, which of course is very important, because to exchange views as to the risk weighting, the the regulatory assessments of firms.
Operating and regulated across borders is a vitally important and well-established mechanism when it comes to global regulatory cooperation. And again, a very useful example is these very well-established colleges, supervisory colleges.
which exists globally and indeed regionally for these important risk and supervisory assessments. And again, I make the distinction that this is not investigatory in nature, but this is supervisory nature, which is more oversight and preventative.
我都覺得少。
嗯，有少矛盾嘅地方。
成套系統咧，證監會先係點樣唔畀誒？點樣先係可以誒去畀招人哋咧？就係當。
對。
非香港嘅監管機構去問受。
受研究嘅機構攞資料嘅時候，佢攞唔到。
你先啟動呢樣嘢。
好啦。
一定攞唔到㗎！如果你搞根據頭先啊啊啊Mr. Shipton所講，就係係證監會對呢個機構嘅風險評估啊等等呢啲，佢一定冇㗎。
係咪先啦？如果要問你攞呢間機構，你哋證監對呢個機構嘅評估就係佢一定唔知嘅喎。
我淨係知道我有牌定冇牌啫嘛，有牌有嗰九類定誒咁類嘢，我咪喺香港做嘅啫嘛。如果問你攞意見，你幾時都要幾幾時都啟動㗎。
係咪先啦？
你頭先就冇我，我就我相反，我調翻轉，我想問有啲咩資料證監可以畀佢嘅咧？
連煲啊！
嗰啲嗰啲誒誒誒誒嗰啲嗰啲trade data。
有幾多個客户啊？
即係我唔知道有啲咩資嗱，唯一啲資料證監冇嘅咧，唔係誒出邊公開市場冇嘅咧，就係證監對呢個機構嘅評估。頭先你所講嗰堆嘢。
咁嗰堆嘢就一定一定被研究嘅機構一定冇㗎啦。
咁咪即係任何時間呢度啟動。
呢個意思即係話佢攞任何資料嘅時候，應該要通知翻嗰個相關嘅。唔係，我就覺得佢個言論矛盾啊！而家係咁講就係，即係佢矛嗱佢佢第一就話啊，我唔係唔唔係啊，要畀人哋嗰啲嘢。
只若只要就係誒，如果嗰個誒誒嗰個機構佢能夠直接問佢問香港個機構攞到嘅咧，我就唔會畀佢嘅。
但係跟住佢答我呢個問題就喂，我可唔可以你畀咗啲嘢人哋嘅時候，你一定要通知翻個受影響嘅機構。佢話唔得啊，因為你因為因為佢攞嗰啲，因為佢畀嗰啲畀嘅畀嗰啲資料咧，就係佢哋個證監對被調查機構唔係調查被研究嘅機構嘅風險評估啊嘛，咁一定冇嘅喎。
我你哋券商，券商一定擁有，一定冇證監對券商嘅風險評估嘅資料㗎。
係嘛？即係你任何嘢都可以，都要畀人哋㗎啦，或者你都可以畀人哋㗎啦，係嘛？
如果要問你哋嘅攞意見就。
除咗問你哋嘅意見，你唔畀得人哋之外，
咁有啲咩意？有咩有啲咩資料？
唔係公開嘅，政監有。
你哋點？
Mr. Sin, thank you. Let me let me try and clarify the situation because we're we're talking about two different types of information exchange.
所以，第一種類型的資訊交換，which is envisaged by the bill。
is in effect.
The request by another regulator for information that we do not already have that is of supervisory interest for financial stability or compliance purposes.
到那，非香港 regulator。
我們同意，因為那信息不是監察對我們的關切。
body is of supervisory interest to another regulator, and is being requested by that other regulator that extra provisions need to attach to that particular information request.
and that particular information request, you are correct in saying probably and most likely, is going to relate to trade data or specific information from a a licensed corporation in the case of Hong Kong.
但正如我提到，在關係到那第一個例子，那第一種類型的資訊交換。
如果那foreign regulator、那non-Hong Kong regulator可以get the information by other mechanisms，
Then we are not, we will not accept the request to to provide it ourselves.
Because that is an important protection, and this is something that the industry requested of us in the consultation, which we totally agree with. Because if there are existing mechanisms by a non-Hong Kong regulator to get that information directly from a licensed corporation, as I said, because they have.
已經提交到那非香港監管者制度，則那係適當嘅機制嚟做呢個。
I then spoke about a second suite of information exchanges, which is in effect the existing arrangements that we have in in in place, and I was making the observation.
That in the vast majority of cases, under the existing exchange of information between regulators, because that was the question which I believe was of interest.
that the vast majority
Of information that is exchanged between a regulator is a risk assessment, or a good example would be a copy of a recent inspections report, or a copy of of a thematic review.
That would be of interest potentially to another regulator, and equally, it's very valuable for us at the SFC to receive copies of these inspections reports or inspection findings when it comes to, again, organisations that operate across boundaries and operate across borders.
那係係的，大大多數的資訊交換，和那係一個典型的資訊交換，和一個典型的交換會發生在與一個監督學院有關，這是一個很好的例子。所以我希望我已把區別講清楚，因為它肯定不是矛盾的性質。
But we are dealing with different types of information exchanges under different circumstances, and that is why it's important to differentiate the protections and the procedures, which we believe is entirely appropriate.
for seeking bespoke information for another regulator, which is the subject matter of the bill, versus
seeking exchanging information under current arrangements.
好。
楊繼昌議員。
啊，Thank you, Mr. Chairman. Can I just get a confirmation from?
the government that the safeguards regarding the provision of supervisory information here would be identical to the existing safeguards.
According to the licence cooperation under section 166, is exactly the same type of safeguards. For the existing safeguards, they are they are identical. But and and then we added additional safeguards for especially for the supervisory cooperation.
所以，的additional safeguards， as I can read， would be down under mainly 2e and then 2b or all these provisions， right？
One one of the safeguards I I would like to ask.
是 about the information obtained under the supervisory you know regime. That is.
Under 2E subsection A.
The regulator of a foreign jurisdiction can only use the information obtained for the purposes of sustaining his supervisory regime and not starting an investigation. Right? That is affirmative.
But on the other hand, of course, they can use you know information obtained from your assistance to to investigation cases for supervisory purpose. Is that correct?
just。
tricking the the questions on in other other way.
Could you repeat the tweet, please, Mr. Lone? My question is.
The information or or the assistance you provide under an investigation, those information.
Can they be used for administer the supervisory regime? There are actually strict right now inside the SFC there are strict information rules relating to information obtained for investigatory purposes. So, for instance, I work in
The supervision department. I am not privy to information that is gathered for investigatory purposes in relation to a licensed corporation. Of course, at the end of the investigation, there is if there is an issue that is announceable, then we receive information. But there is.
Strict internal guidelines in relation to the flow of information from the enforcement division to any other division. But what you are talking about is internal guideline. It is not in the the law book itself, the the legislation itself, to prevent the flow of information deriving from.
一個調查案到一個監察機制，而家你有得個條文，防止調查案的資料從監察機制到開始一個調查案。所以呢個係我問的問題，為何會有呢個？
difference there. Well, forgive me, I don't quite follow the question, but but I will try nonetheless for the purposes of the discussion, take it forward. Of course, the provisions and the safeguards here are trying to enforce, or persuade and regulate.
安排ments with another regulator, and we need to make that crystal clear in legislation and in MOUs that we have a very, you know, very clear design that any information that we provide under this bill is only for supervisory purposes.
I'm not sure I quite follow how our internal guidelines.
from in because our internal guidelines are referable in relation to investigation. In fact, in many respects, I see them as consistent because we we
do treat information gathered for investigatory purposes by the enforcement department separate and distinct and protected internally, and that is in many respects consistent with the bifurcation.
和the distinction that we're applying here, that information is only under the under this proposal for the use for supervisory purposes and not investigatory or for the purposes of proceedings.
no no I understand this, my my question is.
If you assist a foreign regulator in an investigation case, and you obtain a information,
你會 pass some of the information to the foreign regulator. Of course, I mean that that is a natural process. That the foreign regulator.
would obtain some information regarding the investigation, right?
Okay, and upon the receipt of.
this particular information, what I'm asking is, can can they use this information to kick off or start off and and another inquiry for supervisory purposes, or to kick off another, you know, investigation case not related to the first one, but you know, is there is there any restrict
In the use of information, impose on the foreign regulator in this respect, because you are restricting them from using the supervisory information to kick off investigation, because they have to, you know, make a new request. But on the other hand, you don't have a provision.
to stop the foreign regulator to use the piece of information deriving from an investigation case.
to， you know， start an enquiry on on on on on the supervisory regime. Is my question relevant?
Let me let me try and I let me try and respond and I'll also ask our senior counsel, Mr Young, to to supplement. The the the rules relating to exchange of information for investigatory purposes are separate and distinct from what we're discussing today, and I'll ask Mr Young to to speak to those because he's an
expert on that on those rules, but I'm not quite sure whether the
the protections which would apply there would I would expect solve for the concerns that you have that if there's an investigation to investigation exchange of information that's the area that would be would would be in need of of of protection because of course.
You're dealing with matters of potentially going to enforcement processes and procedures, and of course at the end of investigations, any regulator should be put on notice for supervisory purposes what is.
你知唔知？The follow-on action after any disciplinary action. So I can speak for at least. I obviously none of us can speak to another regulator, but I can speak to what we do at the SFC was is that after an enforcement action has been decided upon, that is of course.
Very relevant and important information for ongoing supervisory purposes, and we will make sure that whatever the lessons to be learned from an enforcement action in relation to a licensed corporation are embedded into that organisation, so that mistakes don't.
don't happen or situations don't happen twice, but just going back to the important part, which is the protections in and around exchange of information.
For enforcement and investigatory purposes, I'll ask Mr. Young if he would like to supplement.
先生，yeah，thanks, James. Of course, the the regime for enforcement cooperation has been in place for many years.
啊。
The multilateral memorandum of understanding that most jurisdictions are a party to, including the SFC, sponsored by the International Organisation of Securities Commissions. It has specific provisions in it dealing with permissible uses of information. So therefore, if an investigation requires
來，它就係一個非常
different order of magnitude compared to the sort of activity we're talking about here.
多謝。
清楚，OK，我哋繼續咯。我想問多個問題。係伍家瑤。嗱，你哋行使呢條新嘅條例嘅時候咧，你哋有啲咩額？有冇啲額外嘅internal control？有冇額外嗰啲即係內部嘅審計？即係當然有，我當然你有伴嘅internal audit啦。咁但係，除internal audit之外，你有。
冇啲咩嘅。
內部啊！
即係去審查翻。
即係你哋呢一個係合乎呢條條例所做，有啲。
即係例如你哋嘅要求，明明係。
明明係誒。
佢冇做生意嚟，畀咗人哋啊！等等嗰啲。
有冇啲咩耳聽到羣眾？
你睇清楚。
Mr. Sinn, thank you for that question. The the answer is that we we will, and actually we do have internal guidelines now on the exercise of of information exchange powers, and we actually have outlined draft internal guidelines in relation to the powers envisaged by the bill.
We of course are also subject to the process review panel, which reports to the legislative council, and it would be open to the process review panel to look at the procedures that we apply in relation to any matter that is subject of the PRP's mandate and.
We would expect that they will take an interest in the form and time in this subject matter.
冇問題啦嘛。
好。
噉我哋繼續啦嚇。啊，多謝主席。咁而接住落嚟可以去到第一百二十六頁誒條例草案嘅第四部㗎啦。
咁呢個第四步嘅修訂咧，主要係釐清被撤銷或者被暫暫時吊銷牌字嘅法團嘅人員喺政監門準許進行為結束嗰個被撤銷有關連業務嘅時候咧，由佢哋咧釐清佢哋係有責任遵守條例嘅有關規定嘅。咁或者誒？
可以去到第一百二十六頁嗰度啦。咁而家我哋誒新誒新增嘅第一、第一A同一B款咧，就係就中介人嘅牌照或者註冊被撤銷作規定。咁證監會咧可以準許中介人進行對結束被撤銷活動嘅業務係屬必要嘅業務嘅運作咧，誒先可以。
而進進行嘅咁條文咧，亦都指明誒，於指明人士咧可以進行有關業務嘅運作嘅。
咁第一二七頁裏邊嘅條款其實都係差唔多，不過誒對象就係嗰個中介人嘅牌照或者註冊係被暫時吊銷誒做規定啦。咁誒都可以準誒，政監會可以準許呢啲中介人咧進誒進行咧，對於保障呢個中介人客户權益屬必要嘅業務嘅。
咁第一百二十八至到一百三十條嘅第二A二B款咧，就係定名牌照或者註冊被撤銷誒，或者被暫時吊銷嘅中介人同埋指明人士咧，必須被當作冇被撤銷或者被暫時吊銷或者撤銷牌照。咁其實呢個主要目的咧，即係誒表明咧，呢啲誒即係。
如啊，依個條例裏邊嘅有關條文咧，同埋要求咧、規限咧，繼續適用於喺佢哋嘅身上嘅。
同事有冇問題啊？
冇問題，我哋繼續啦。係誒，而家可以咧，就去到第一百四十頁誒條例草案嘅第五部嘅呢個條誒呢個建議咧，就係因為而家其實只有證監會可以根據條例第三百七十八條咧同意進一步披露已經原先已經被披露嘅資料㗎啦。咁但係
事實上咧，而家聯交所咧就上市發團可能違反上市規則進行調查嘅時候咧，喺呢個情況下，上市發團其實係誒係必須通知佢哋本身個核數師啦，或者個保險公司嘅。但係限於而家條例所限咧，好多時候咧都必須要再揾翻阿證監會誒問佢攞。
得同意嘅，但係其實喺成件事上邊咧，因為其實呢個上市規則咧係由誒呢個聯交所所誒施行啦，所以其實證監會係無需要牽涉喺度嘅。咁所以我哋今次呢個誒修訂咧，主要只不過係誒希望可以誒將嗰個呢個情況之下咧，可以畀呢個聯誒交易所。
任何交易所咧都有權同意進一步披露原先已經被披露嘅資料嘅，咁呢個誒目標只係誒志在提高呢個行政效率嘅啫。
咁誒第一百四十條裏邊嘅修訂就係誒反映我哋頭先個政策原意啦。
咁可以去到第一百四十六頁，誒。
啊啊！順住應該係第一百四十五頁第六部就授權職能修訂誒呢個條例草案嘅。咁呢個修訂咧，其實誒好簡單，就主要因為根據現行條例誒裏邊咧，證監會咧其實係可以誒發表通函同埋常見嘅問題。
材料向中介人説明佢哋執誒執行職能嘅方式，但因為現有嘅條例咧，依一個噉樣嘅職能咧係唔可以轉售嘅，咁所以我哋而家建議咧就將依個職能咧可以轉售出嚟，咁可以更加有效率誒執行依個職能嘅。
跟住就係去到第。
誒一百四十六頁第第七部嘅，咁呢個誒修訂咧就係定明將買賣證券同埋期貨期權合約嘅徵費款額調節到最接近一整先，咁因為而家誒嗰個證券及期貨徵費令咧係定明買賣證券同埋期貨期權合約。
嘅徵費率，亦都指明咧計算徵費嘅若干百分率。咁依啲百分率咧就會可能產生因為唔不足一仙就冇辦法收取嘅尾數嘅。咁所以我哋建議喺啊依個徵費律裏邊加入第二A條啦。噉就將啊買賣啊繳付嘅徵費咧，不論係以百分率啦，定係港元。
數值嘅方式表述咧，個款額咧都會調節到最接近嘅一整先嘅。
係誒係四仔五入，其實意思係係誒一整先，即係譬如零點零一五到零點零一九，噉就會調節到零點零二噉樣。嗯，即係細個一先就四仔五入到去嗰個先嗰度。但係你呢度咁寫嘢冇講話係四仔五入嘅喎。誒。
因為依個其實誒，我哋都參考過其他誒類似嘅法例啦。咁草擬誒律誒法律草擬專員畀我哋嗰個建議咧，誒呢個其實都可以代表到係四升五入嗰個意思㗎。
係。
嗯。
誒繼續啦。誒一四七到一四八頁咧，就係修訂徵費令現時第十同埋第十三條相關條文，就係以零點一零元取代而家喺誒徵費令裏邊零點一零八元嘅。咁呢個徵費令其實呢一個零點一零八零喺舊年誒十一月一號就生效嘅。
不過後邊我哋支出誒依個或啲經有啲經紀行個系統咧，係最多支援係兩個小數位嘅徵費，咁所以為面對業界誒構成不必要嘅誒負擔啦，噉我哋就誒會改咗去就係收誒徵收零點一零嘅徵費嘅。
好。
咁誒一四九到一五一頁咧，誒就係修訂證券及期貨投資者賠償徵費規則。其實嗰個誒修訂都係同頭先所講嘅，基於相同理由啦。咁加入呢個二A條規定有關徵費嘅款額，若果唔包括一不一不足一先嘅數咧，就係調節自
最接近嘅一整先嘅。
我。
咁之後可以去到第一百五啊二頁啦。一個誒，主要係一啲輕微嘅修訂嘅啫。譬如第一百五啊二頁裏邊啦，噉我哋將嗯修改嗰個中，即係修改個中文文本第三百零七啊第一款啦，加入根據本部嘅字眼咧，係同英文版嘅用語一致。
嘅啫。
咁第一百五十八頁都係一個糾正輕微嘅錯誤啦。噉就將嗰個誒證券及期貨成交單據、户口結單及收據規則裏邊，將第六款裏邊對第五款嘅提述改翻啱做呢個第四款嘅。
咁誒之後可以去到第一百六十五頁，其實佢去到二百二十頁都係相同嘅修訂嚟嘅啫，就係關乎有投票權股份嘅修訂。咁因為呢個誒，其實喺呢個條例嘅第十五部啦，有關權益披露嘅條文裏邊咧，誒原先咧就。
係誒以股份面值嚟決定某一個人係咪需要負上披露嘅責任嘅，咁但係當誒公司條例修改之後咧，就廢除啊廢除咗股份面值啦，咁所以咧都需要相應修訂翻呢個條例裏邊嘅用語，用誒個誒條例第三百零八條誒零三零八括一條所。
界定嘅有股份權股份嘅數目嚟取代某一啲人擁有誒權益嘅股份面積，作為評定是否產生披露責任嘅機制嘅。咁呢個誒依誒一百六十五至二百二十頁咧，都係做呢個相應嘅修訂嘅啫。
好啊，同事冇意見啦，冇問題。
繼續啊！
誒，其實就應該。
哦，OK。
同事有冇問題？
同事，如果冇問題咧，就。
張議員，你係咪有咩問題？
暫時暫時睇唔到有咩太大嘅爭議性。O K。
另外個同事係冇問題咧，即係我哋。
就誒完成咗呢一條條例草案嘅審議。
噉就誒。
嚇！我我就會誒，想睇睇大家會唔會有啲咩修訂。
張議員有咩政策上有咩意見可以大聲啲噉，即係大家分享，有冇嗰啲發展空間嘅啫？OK，嗱，冇問題啊嘛，冇問題啊，冇問題。大家有冇咩修訂？
誒建議冇。
政府亦都唔會有修訂建議啊！
誒法律顧問對於我哋今日審議嘅其他條文都冇冇其他意見。
O.K.好啊。
呢個階段裏邊，我未能夠提到任何修訂。啊，唔緊要，得，因為我哋都有個時間，有時間畀大家嘅。噉就啊，係，好啊。
誒嗱，我哋。
今日就完呢個會啦，就誒基本上審議嘅工作就完完結啦。噉我哋會睇睇政府咧，你係想幾時咧就正式搦上嚟恢復二度好嘛？好。咁然後我哋先至咧就畀時間咧就畀同事嚇，因為嗰啲要倒數翻嗰啲。
啲時間，我哋幾時向誒內會報告啊？誒，我哋啲同事幾時有個限期畀佢哋去誒提交呢個修訂啊？咁嚇，噉你誒，我哋會通知翻秘書嘅，好嘛？好啊，係啦，好。
嗱，個同事冇其他問題咧，噉我就誒結束今日嘅會議，亦都咧係就住誒即係同事所誒。
關注嘅嗰個時間問題，我哋會遲啲通知大家，好唔好啊？噉我如果係誒，同時冇冇進一步嘅修訂嘅話咧，噉我哋就唔會再開會㗎啦，好唔好啊？啊，噉我哋秘書亦都會同政府咧係再夾嘅時間。O K，唔該曬咁多誒，我宣佈散會嚇。